mcmurrayhatchery.com 2018-10-29

# Murray McMurray Hatchery - Privacy Policy

Murray McMurray Hatchery appreciates the trust that you place in us. We work diligently to protect your personal information that you provide us. This notice describes our privacy policy.

For any privacy related concerns, please contact us at:

Murray McMurray Hatchery   
PO BOX 458   
191 Closz Drive   
Webster City, Iowa 50595   
Phone: 515-832-3280

Email: [info@mcmurrayhatchery.com](mailto:info@mcmurrayhatchery.com)

## What types of personal information does McMurray Hatchery gather?

We gather information from your visits to our web site and other means of communication that enables us to process your orders, track orders, provide you with goods and services that you request, contact you with regard to the status of your order, request, or inquiry, send catalogs or other promotional information that we think will interest you, improve the range of goods and services that we offer you, improve our customer service, and improve our communications with you. 

When you interact with us through our web site we automatically collect information such as the time of your visit or interaction, your IP address, referral information, and information stored in "cookies". We also may collect information resulting from phone calls, e-mail, or other contact or communications with you.

## What information do you share with other companies?

We have contracts with other companies to provide certain services, like shipping, verifying contact information, sending e-mail, market research, managing promotions, and payment processing. We provide these companies with just the information that they need in order to provide those services. 

If you have registered for our e-mail newsletter or made purchases through our web site, rest assured that your e-mail address and telephone number will not be made available to other companies for marketing purposes.

We do, however, share offline contact information, which includes your name and mailing address, with third parties who may send you promotional offers or information about their products or services. If you do not want us to share your offline contact information with third parties, or if you do not want to receive such information or promotional offers by mail, then please call, write, or e-mail us your request to opt-out.

## What information do you share with government agencies?

McMurray Hatchery is required to file a VS 9-3 form in the destination state (US only) for every order of baby chicks that we ship. That form includes the full ship-to address: name, address, city, state, zip code and phone number. These forms are first sent to an approved reviewer, usually a state veterinarian or health official, who reviews the forms, signs them and forwards them to the appropriate state agency. The VS 9-3 form is an integral part of the [National Poultry Improvement Plan](http://www.poultryimprovement.org/), of which McMurray Hatchery is an active participant. 

In addition to the required form, McMurray Hatchery also sends a pre-shipment notification report to each state, approximately one week before the actual shipment. This report contains the same information as the VS 9-3 and allows the state agencies to more effectively monitor the birds being shipped to their state. 

## What about cookies?

We use cookies on our website. A cookie is a small amount of information that your web browser will place on your computer. It allows us to identify your web browser and personalize your browsing experience, making the addition of items to your shopping cart and making purchase on our website possible. 

You can disable cookies if you desire. Information about how to do that is available in the toolbar of most web browsers under "Help". Because our site depends on the use of cookies to add items to your shopping cart and check out on our web site, we recommend that you leave cookies enabled. If you prefer to disable cookies, you may wish to make purchases from us by phoning in your order rather than purchasing over the web site.

## How secure is the information about me?

We employ SSL, firewalls, and other security measures to keep your personal information secure. 

## Opt Out Policy

## Your choices about communication from McMurray Hatchery

If you do not wish to receive catalogs from McMurray Hatchery, please contact us. 

If you do not wish to have your name and mailing address shared with third parties for marketing purposes, please contact us.

If you do not want to receive e-mail newsletters from us, please use our [Newsletter E-mail Settings page ](http://www.mcmurrayhatchery.com/weeklyspecialsignup!input.html)to opt-out of our newsletter mailings. Your request will be processed as soon as possible but may take up to three days to be removed.

## Notices and Revisions

If you choose to visit McMurrayHatchery.com, your visit and any privacy related issues, concerns, or disputes are subject to this privacy notice. If you have any concerns or questions, please contact us. Our business changes over time, and this Privacy Notice will also change from time to time. Please check our web site periodically to see the current Privacy Notice. 

In the event of a corporate change, such as a merger, consolidation, or the sale of all or substantially all of our assets, we may sell, transfer, or otherwise disclose personal information, which may include but is not limited to your name and mailing address.
